9號秘事
第七季   第二集
9班
金老師
規劃表 2021年-2022年
2021年 9班 - 哈迪老師
希望
早上好 九班同學們
Bore da, dosbarth naw.
早上好 愛德華茲校長
Bore da, Mr Edwards.
這是你們的新老師 柯蒂斯老師
Dyma'ch athro newydd Mr Curtis
他會教你們英語
ac mae'n mynd I'ch dysgu chi yn Saesneg.
我跟他們說
I was telling them
你所有的課都會用英語上
you're going to be taking all your lessons in English,
英語對于將來想離開村子
which is a very important skill
外出探險的人來說
for those adventurers amongst you
是個非常重要的技能
who might be thinking about leaving the village in the future.
柯蒂斯老師曾在倫敦的一所學校教書
Mr Curtis used to teach at a school in London
所以我相信他有許多激動人心的故事
so I'm sure he'll have all sorts of exciting stories
會講給我們聽的
to tell us.
倫敦人會花兩英鎊買杯咖啡 是嗎
They pay £2 for a coffee, don't they?
還有別的
And the rest.
我的天啊 好家伙
Oh, dearie me, imagine that!
大家都知道
Now, as you all know,
你們的金老師在經過美好的一年后
your previous teacher, Mr King, had to leave us
不得不離開我們了
after a wonderful year.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
不過他在旅途中
But he has sent us this postcard from his travels,
給我們寄來了這張明信片
and I wondered if one of you
你們誰來給全班同學念一下
would like to read it to the class.
-我 -我
-Me! -Me.
凱莉 你要不要來念一下
Ceri, would you care to do the honours?
好孩子
Good girl.
親愛的九班 我在澳洲問候大家
"Dear Class 9, greetings from down under.
我在這里過得很好
"I'm having an amazing time
我想新學期也該開始了吧
"and I'm thinking of you, as you start your next chapter.
我非常懷念和你們在一起的時光
"I cherish the memory of our time together
能夠真正地了解你們每個人
"and getting to know all of you so closely.
愛你們的金老師
"Much love, Mr King."
多好的人
What a man!
多好的老師 太好了
What a teacher, what a man.
那么 該上課了
Anyway, back down to reality.
柯蒂斯老師 交給你了
Mr Curtis, over to you.
謝謝你 校長
Thank you, Headmaster.
那么 我有個問題
So, here's a question
我和皮諾曹有什么不同呢
what's the difference between me and Pinocchio?
我很開心能來威爾士
I'm glad to be in Wales.
啊 因為皮諾曹被鯨魚吃掉了
Ah, now that is because Pinocchio was eaten by a whale.
我說得對嗎 柯蒂斯老師
Have I got that right, Mr Curtis?
對 我只是開了個玩笑
Yes, it was just a joke.
這就是個玩笑 九班的同學們
It was a joke, Class 9.
是個玩笑
A joke.
繼續上課
Carry on.
大家都知道
So, as you all know,
期末演出的主題都是跟環境有關的
our end-of-term assembly is going to be all about the environment.
那么 環境是什么意思呢
So, what does that mean?
誰來說一下
Anyone.
-尤恩 -呃
-Euan? -Erm...
是我們教室
Our classroom?
對 教室是我們最熟悉的環境 還有呢
Yes, that's our immediate surroundings, what else?
還有田野
Ooh, fields!
對 很好 環境包括了 人類或動植物
Yes, good. It's any place where people and plants
生活和生長的所有地方
and animals actually live and grow.
那么哪些事情會影響我們的環境呢
So what types of things will affect our environment?
哦 人豆 老師
Oh, human beans, sir.
你說什么 格溫
What's that, Gwen?
人豆
Human beans.
不是人豆 我們不是蔬菜
Not human beans, we're not vegetables,
是人類 對
but human beings, yes,
我們人類確實對環境有影響
we certainly have an impact.
我們對環境的影響有正面的
And we can affect our environment
也有負面的
in positive ways and in negative ways.
那么 哪些正面的事情是可以做的呢
So, what are some of the positive things that we can do?
凱莉
Ceri?
回收利用
Recycling.
非常好 凱莉 回收利用
Very good, Ceri. Yes. Recycling.
還有別的嗎
Anyone else?
你們聽說過格蕾塔·桑伯格這個人嗎
Well, who here has heard of Greta Thunberg?
都沒聽說過嗎
None of you?
好吧
OK. Er...
你們應該都聽說過全球變暖吧
You've probably all heard of global warming?
沒聽說過 那么氣候變化呢
No? How about climate change?
好吧 你們去年應該看過一些這方面的報道
OK, well, you should have covered some of this last year,
我來問問大家
but let me ask you this...
你們說颶風是什么原因造成的
What do you think causes hurricanes?
上帝放的屁
God farting!
不對 別胡說 歐文
No, don't be silly, Owen.
這是個很嚴肅的話題
This is actually a really serious subject.
作為你們的家庭作業 我希望你們放學后
So, for your homework, I want you all to go home
學習一下有關全球變暖和臭氧層的知識
and learn all about global warming and the ozone layer.
老師 金老師說我們不用做家庭作業的
Sir, Mr King said we didn't have to do homework.
很遺憾
Well, I'm really sorry,
不過金老師不再是你的老師了 我才是
but Mr King isn't your teacher now, I am.
你們或許還沒有意識到
You know, I don't know if you realise it,
這會是影響你們和你們未來的
but this is the number one topic
最重要的話題之一
that's going to affect you and all your futures,
所以你們對此一無所知是不行的
so it really isn't something that you can afford to be ignorant about!
抱歉
Sorry.
好了 大家回去寫一篇小作文
Now, I want you all to do a paragraph
下周一交上來
and bring it in on Monday.
好了 現在把課本拿出來
Right, you can all get your books out
默讀20分鐘 開始
and do silent reading for 20 minutes. Off you go.
校長
Oh, Headmaster?
我能跟您說句話嗎
Er, could I have a word?
可以啊 艾倫 有什么事嗎
Of course, Alan. How can I help?
您有金老師的電子郵箱嗎
I wondered if you had an email address for Mr King.
電子郵箱
Email...
是那個帶藍色小鳥的圖標嗎
Is that the one with the little blue bird?
不對 那個應該是推特
No, I think that's Twitter.
對 你說得對
That's right, yes, tash-tag.
電子郵箱應該是帶@的那個吧
Email is the @ sign,
我記得我辦公室里
isn't it? Yes, I think I've got
有張紙上寫的就是這個
a piece of paper with that on in my office.
哦 謝謝 我想和他聊聊他
Oh, thanks, it's just I'd love to talk to him
去年教的內容和用的是什么教程
about what he covered last year and what curriculum he's been using.
嗯 沒問題
Well, no problem.
我讓梅根找出來 回頭再給你
I'll ask Megan to dig it out and I'll get back to you.
謝謝
Thanks.
其他的都進展順利嗎
All good otherwise?
對 是的
Er, yeah, I think so.
你期末演出的節目開始排練了嗎
Have you started rehearsing for your assembly yet?
金老師的節目一向是很華麗的
Mr King's were always very lavish.
就像是倫敦西區的戲劇作品一樣
Like West End theatre productions!
我會 我會弄得超好看的
Well, I'll... I'll try and make mine Wicked.
是部音樂劇
That's a musical. Ah.
你又說笑話了
Another one of your jokes.
那我就等著看了
Well, I look forward to it.
看到孩子們站在舞臺上 是件賞心悅目的事情
Always a joy to see the children take centre stage.
艾倫 你也知道這是一所很小的學校
We're a small school, Alan, as you can see,
我們已經有好幾次差點關門了
and we've very nearly been closed down a few times,
不過能把你這樣的
but bringing in teachers such as yourself,
經歷豐富的老師招進來
with all your experience of the world,
確實有助于孩子們成長 你明白嗎
it really helps the children grow, you know?
嗯 我也是這么希望的 校長 真的
Well, that's... That's all I want, Headmaster, it really is.
那就好 行吧 我回頭把電子郵箱找出來
Jolly good. Right, well, I'll get that bmail for you,
讓梅根發短信給你
and I'll get Megan to send it to you as a text.
做出英國教育的標準吧
Take that, Ofsted!
-非常好 你畫的是個南瓜嗎 很好 -對
-That's very good. Is that going to be a pumpkin? Great. -Yes.
上面還有嚇人的眼睛
With some scary eyes on it.
掛起來的時候
Make sure that your paint isn't dripping
可別讓油彩滴下來
when you hang up your paintings, OK?
-歐文 你的畫還沒干嗎 -呃 是啊老師
-Is yours still wet, Owen? -Er, yes, sir.
那先把它放在托盤上
Well, put it on top of the tray for now.
畫得非常好 等畫干了以后
That's fantastic. And then, when it is dry,
我們再把這些都掛起來展覽
we will stick them all up on the display.
哦 謝謝你 凱莉 太好了
Oh, thank you, Ceri, that's great.
好了 休息15分鐘 脫了圍裙 去玩一會兒吧
OK, you've got 15 minutes. Aprons off, go and have a play.
走吧 去玩吧 去吧
Walking. That's it, off you go.
凱莉 我有話要問你
Ceri, could I have a word with you, please?
我說 你想什么呢
I mean, what were you thinking? Hmm?
這些蝌蚪現在變不成青蛙了 對吧
Those tadpoles are not going to turn into frogs now, are they?
為什么不行
Why not?
你把它們放在壺里煮了呀
Because you boiled them in the kettle.
你為什么這么干 凱莉
I mean, why would you do that, Ceri?
因為全球變暖了
Global warming.
我是讓你去研究 沒讓你實踐
I asked you to research it, not recreate it.
金老師還吃過金魚呢
Mr King once ate a goldfish.
是嗎 我不管金老師干過什么
Yeah, well, I don't care what Mr King did.
我有些擔心你了 凱莉
I'm getting a bit concerned about you, Ceri.
上個禮拜你把西蒙的臉
I mean, last week,
按進他的生日蛋糕里了 對吧
you pushed Simon's face into his birthday cake, didn't you?
他的頭發要是被蠟燭點著了怎么辦
What if his hair had caught fire on the candles?
你看過邁克爾·杰克遜的視頻嗎
Have you seen that Michael Jackson video?
不是舔人屁股的那個
Not the one about licking boys' bottoms,
是他的頭發著火的那個視頻
the one where his hair caught fire.
他險些就毀容了
It very nearly disfigured him...
甚至更嚴重
..even more.
邁克爾·杰克遜是誰
Who's Michael Jackson?
算了
Never mind.
你家里怎么樣 有什么想跟我說的嗎
Is there anything going on at home that you want to tell me about?
-我家的房子在擴建呢 -哦
-We're having an extension. -OK.
你爸爸媽媽相處融洽嗎 沒有吵架吧
Are Mummy and Daddy getting on all right? No shouting?
有讓你煩心的事嗎
Something upsetting you?
我不想看到世界末日
I don't want the world to end.
那肯定不會
Well, it's not going to end.
-誰跟你說會世界末日的 -反抗滅絕組織
-Who said it's going to end? -The stinking rebellion.
什么組織
Who?
是你讓我們看的 還是家庭作業
You asked us to read about it for homework.
你是說氣候變化的抗議者嗎
You mean the climate change protesters?
嚇到我了
It frightened me.
千萬別害怕 凱莉
Oh, you mustn't be frightened, Ceri.
我的意思是 你應該感受那種情緒
I mean, you should feel
然后用它做一些有意義的事情
that emotion and then do something positive with it.
沒關系的
It's all right.
好了 好了 對不起 嚇到你了
There, there. Sorry it frightened you.
想去外面玩一會兒嗎
Now, do you want to go and play outside or...
還是和我說說話
..or do you want to stay inside with me?
我們說說話吧
Stay with you.
好孩子
Good girl.
你是餓了嗎
Little bit peckish, are we?
哦 抱歉 校長
Oh, sorry, Headmaster,
我就是
I was just, erm,
在練給孩子們表演的小魔術
just practising a trick for the children.
這倒是教食物鏈知識的一個辦法
Well, that's one way of teaching the food chain.
艾倫 方便的話 我有幾句話想單獨和你談談
I... I just wanted to have a quiet word with you, Alan,
-行嗎 -當然可以
-if you don't mind. -Yes, of course.
你來面試的時候
When you came in for your interview,
你說你很想來我們這種
you said you were keen to move to a smaller school,
規模比較小的學校任教
like ours, away from the cut and thrust,
遠離俗世的紛紛擾擾
shall we say, of inner-city education
享受更寧靜的生活方式
and embrace a quieter pace of life.
對 這也是醫生給我的建議
Yes, it's, erm, literally what the doctor ordered.
我知道在涉及心理健康的問題上
Now, I know it's important we talk sensitively
應該謹慎
about mental health,
不過我還是想跟你明確一下
so I just wanted to clarify...
你有些精神上的問題 是嗎
You went a bit doolally, didn't you?
是 是
No. No, I...
是因為工作量大了些
It was just the workload.
我有些疲憊 身心俱疲
I was exhausted, both physically, mentally.
我有一段時間確實迷失了自我
I did lose myself for a time,
不過 來到這里對我非常有好處
but, erm, coming here's done me the world of good.
您為什么這么問
Why do you ask?
是這樣
Well, the thing is...
有人舉報了你
..an allegation has been made against you,
我就有責任展開調查了
and it's my duty to investigate it.
-什么舉報 -我暫時不能說
-What allegation?  -I can't divulge that at the moment.
-那 是誰舉報的我 -她也不想暴露身份
-Well, who's made it? -She doesn't want to say.
-是個女學生嗎 -也許是也許不是
-So it's a girl?  -She may or may not be.
關鍵是我向凱莉的父母保證過
The point is I promised Ceri's parents
舉報者的身份要絕對保密
that she, or he, would have absolute anonymity.
-所以是凱莉 對嗎 -是的
-So it's Ceri?  -Yes.
好吧
Right.
既然你已經了解到了一部分情況
So now you've wormed that out of me, can you tell me
你有什么要說的嗎
in your own words
周二上午課間休息時發生了什么
what happened Tuesday morning, break time?
-什么叫發生了什么 -什么也沒發生啊
-What do you mean, what happened? -Nothing happened.
她的行為有些古怪
She'd been behaving strangely for a while.
她把蝌蚪都弄死了
She killed all the tadpoles.
我把她留下想跟她談談而已
I kept her behind to talk to her about it.
你沒有讓她做什么
And at no point did you ask her
犯忌諱的事情嗎
if she wanted to play the hairy meat whistle?
什么 沒有
What? No.
你沒說過
And you didn't say,
你想看看老師的蝌蚪嗎 這種話
"Do you want to see how sir can make his own tadpoles?"
-當然沒有 這太可怕了 -你確定嗎
-Definitely not, that's horrible. -Are you sure?
確定 說沒說過我記得很清楚
Yes, I think I'd remember saying that.
那你覺得這種話她是從哪兒聽來的
Well, where do you suppose she's got this from, then?
我相信兒童讀物里肯定沒有
Because I don't recall that being in the Biff and Chip books.
我不知道
I don't know.
也許她在網上看了一些不好的內容
Maybe she saw something inappropriate online,
這也是常有的事
it happens all the time.
可我們這里沒有無線網絡
Not with our Wi-Fi connection, it doesn't.
我下載《鄉村檔案》都用了一個周末
It takes me all weekend to download one Countryfile.
你和她提過邁克爾·杰克遜對男的
Did you talk to her about Michael Jackson doing things
菊花所做之事嗎
with boys' anuses?
提到過 可沒提其他的事
Yes, but I never said anuses.
這就夠了
Well, that's something.
我已經說服了凱莉的父母
Now, I've talked the girl's parents down
不要提出正式起訴
from making an official complaint,
如果可以的話
but I don't want to drag the police into it
我也不想把警察牽扯進來
if I can help it.
我們是一所獨立學校
We're an independent school and we like to deal
我們喜歡在內部處理這類事情
with these types of things within the community.
什么 以前發生過這種事嗎
What, so this has happened before?
你初來乍到 我不會開玩笑的
You're new here, and I'm not being funny,
可我不能僅憑你說的就相信你 艾倫
but I don't know you from Alan.
-是亞當 -哦 抱歉 我以為是艾倫呢
-It's Adam. -Oh, sorry, I thought it was Alan.
亞當 我相信你能理解 作為這所學校的校長
I'm sure you understand, Adam, that, as head of this school,
我必須首先確定事實真相
I have to establish the facts of this matter
然后才能把凱莉交回到你手上
before I can allow Ceri back into your clutches, so to speak.
對 沒錯 您需要我寫一份聲明嗎
Yes, of course. You want me to make a statement?
不用 不過我需要你給我看你的雞巴
No, I want you to show me your penis.
什么
What?
凱莉描述得非常細致
The girl has given quite a vivid description
她還用橡皮泥捏了個模型
and I believe made a Plasticine model,
可是我不想碰
but I didn't want to touch it.
我要看看她捏的和你的是不是一樣
I need to see if this tallies with the real thing.
所以還得弄個辨認隊列嗎 如果不是我的
So I've got to do an identity parade? What if it's not mine?
你還要像尋找灰姑娘那樣四處去尋找嗎
Are you going to take it around the kingdom like Cinderella?
別耍小聰明 亞當
Don't be facetious, Adam,
我是在想辦法了解事實真相
I'm trying to get to the bottom of this, one way or the other.
要么是你說謊 要么是凱莉在說謊
Either you're lying or the girl's lying.
這怎么可能
I just can't believe this.
我可以隨時聯系你的工會代表
I can always contact your union representative...
不
No...
No.
算了 快點看 行了吧
Well, just make it quick, all right?
這多干凈利落 這樣你我都省事
All very neat and tidy, that's what I like to see.
你究竟在找什么
What are you looking for, exactly?
啊 這下就明白了
Ah, now that would be telling.
俗話說
They say...
世上沒有一模一樣的兩片雪花
..they're like snowflakes no two are alike.
太荒唐了
This is ridiculous.
抱歉 溫妮 我們這兒正忙著呢
Oh, sorry, Winnie, we're a bit busy here.
你好 柯蒂斯老師 你還沒走啊
Hello, Mr Curtis, you're here late.
我現在可以打掃了嗎
Is it all right for me to clean now?
現在不方便
Not just at the moment.
哦 別擔心溫妮 她什么都看不見
Oh, don't worry about Winnie, she's blind as a bat.
沒事的 溫妮 你忙你的
It's fine, Winnie, you go right ahead.
是你嗎 愛德華茲校長
Is that you, Mr Edwards?
原來你也在啊 你還在忙嗎
I didn't see you down there. You keeping busy?
是啊 我一向都很忙的
Yes, I've got my hands full, as usual.
沒關系 我能把你身邊打掃干凈的
Don't worry, I can clean around you.
我得省出時間來清理男生的廁所
I have to save some time to tackle the boys' toilets.
他們拉的粑粑實在是
The size of some of those stools...
真不知道他們在家里都吃了什么
I don't know what their mothers feed them.
實在是太難清理了
Like airport Toblerones, some of them.
可以了嗎
Are you all done here?
可以了 是的
I think so, yes.
等我調查清楚這件事 我會再來找你的
I'll be in touch once I've got my head around this.
謝謝你 亞當
Thank you, Adam.
我們就是 討論一下新的繪畫創作
We were just, erm, discussing a possible arts project.
哦 我還以為他在給你的雞巴拍照呢
Oh, I thought he was taking photographs of your cock.
好了 九班 我發的是關于分數的卷子
OK, Class 9, I'm handing out these worksheets on fractions.
給你們15分鐘
You have got 15 minutes.
能做多少做多少
Do as many as you can.
記得把名字寫在最上面
Remember to put your names at the top, please.
老師 凱莉怎么了
Sir, what happened to Ceri?
你想問什么
What do you mean?
-她去哪兒了 -我不知道
-Where is she?  -I don't know.
別說話了 歐文
Now tight lips, please, Owen.
聽我說 現在不是你說話的時候
We listen with these, not these.
安靜
Quiet.
沒聽見嗎 安靜
I said, quiet!
那是什么
What have you got there?
歐文 什么東西
Owen, what is that?
-沒什么 老師 -當我是白癡嗎 拿出來
-Nothing, sir!  -I'm not an idiot, show me.
在誰手里
All right, who's got it?
拿出來 給我交出來 快點兒
Give it to me. Give it to me now.
這是什么 格溫
What's this? Gwen?
格溫
Gwen?
是胡蘿卜 老師
Carrot, sir.
胡蘿卜
A carrot?
那你笑什么
Well, why are you laughing, then?
是不是因為這像個雞巴
Is it because this bit looks like a penis?
又大又軟的雞巴
A big floppy penis?!
怎么了 柯蒂斯老師
Everything all right, Mr Curtis?
啊 我們在教分數 還有生物
Yes, we were just doing fractions and...biology.
兩門課一起上 有意思
Interesting combination.
我把凱莉·摩根給你帶來了
I have young Ceri Morgan for you.
去坐下吧 凱莉
Ceri, would you like to take a seat? Good girl.
這下沒事了吧 校長
Everything, er, all right now, Headmaster?
沒事了沒事了 都解決了 沒什么麻煩了
Yes, yes, all cleared up, no further action required.
可以說這兩張照片
Suffice to say there was quite a big discrepancy
之間的差別很大
between the two images.
為了你好 我必須要確保萬無一失
In your favour, I have to add. So, you know, every cloud...
哦 好吧 謝謝
Oh, well. Good, thanks.
繼續上課吧
As you were.
你能回來就好 凱莉
It's nice to have you back, Ceri.
我說一句
Just to say,
如果想不出答案
if you're struggling to find the right answer...
也不要胡編亂造
..don't just make something up,
因為說謊是有代價的
because that has consequences.
有問題可以舉手提問
Just put your hand up and talk to me.
如果我不知道發生了什么 我就幫不了你們
I can't help you if I don't know what's going on.
所以不要在我背后說三道四
So don't go behind my back.
明白嗎 那就好
OK? Good.
哦 你好 溫妮
Oh. Hi, Winnie.
哦 你好
Oh, hello, dear.
你要不要些韭菜呢
I just wondered if you wanted to take a leek.
什么
Sorry?
參加豐收節啊
For the harvest festival.
今年我的收成不錯
I've had a good crop this year.
土豆又大又漂亮還有小蘿卜
Nice big potatoes, radishes...
我的大頭菜還得獎了呢
My turnips have won prizes, you know.
哦 那恭喜你了
Well, congratulations.
溫妮
Winnie...
金老師和孩子們相處得好嗎
What was, erm, Mr King like with the children?
哦 上課的時候我不知道
Oh, well, I'm not in the lessons, like.
不過他們好像都挺喜歡他的
They all seemed to love him.
他就像是個大明星
He was a real star!
這個也很棒
Quite a dish, too.
好得有些難以置信了
He sounds too good to be true.
嗯 你的蘿卜還真不錯 溫妮
Well, your, erm, neeps are very impressive, Winnie.
謝謝
Thank you.
這是一款全新的內衣
This is a brand-new Playtex.
塑胸的效果不錯
Lift and separate.
我說的是蔬菜
I, er, meant the vegetables.
哦 那是大自然的魔法
Well, that's Mother Nature working her magic.
溫妮 我答應校長
Winnie, I promised the headmaster
今天下班前會把報告交給他
I'd get those reports to him by the end of the day
可我差點兒就忘了
it's completely slipped my mind.
你有沒有
You don't, erm...You don't happen to have a...
他辦公室的鑰匙
key to his office, do you?
求你了
Please?
哦 我有
Oh, go on, then.
你動作快些就行了
As long as you're quick.
謝謝你 我馬上就還回來
Thank you. I'll be two minutes.
沒有姓金的
No King.
校長嗎 是我 艾倫·柯蒂斯
Headmaster, it's Alan Curtis.
是亞當啊 有什么事嗎
Oh, hello, Adam, what can I do for you?
我有幾件要緊的事要跟你說
I need to talk to you urgently about several things,
首先就是金老師
firstly about Mr King.
這所學校根本沒有他在這里工作過的任何記錄
This school has no record of him ever having worked here.
你說什么 抱歉 我實在是聽不清楚
What's that? Sorry, it's a very bad line.
金老師怎么了
Something about Mr King?
九班去年的班主任是哈迪老師
The class teacher last year was a Mr Hardy,
根本就是另外一個人
a completely different person.
我不知道這個姓金的怎么會在這里
I don't know what this King has been doing here,
還允許他接觸孩子們
being given access to children, but...
但我認為這里發生過校園暴力事件
..I think there's been abuse going on,
而且被掩蓋了下來 我認為你 愛德華茲校長
it's been covered up, and I think you, Mr Edwards,
也是參與者
are part of it!
我聽不見你說什么 亞當 通話質量太差了
I'm losing you, Adam, it's a terrible connection.
我現在在地里呢 一會兒就回來找你 好吧
I'm just in the field - I'll come and see you shortly, OK?
你跑不掉的 你聽見了嗎
You won't get away with this, do you hear?
哦 九班 你們在干嘛
Oh, Class 9, what's this?
我們想讓你看看我們的節目
We want to show you our assembly.
哦 我今天想安排你們默讀
Oh, well, I was just going to do quiet reading today,
要不明天再說吧
but, erm, maybe tomorrow we could...
求你了 老師
Oh, please, sir,
我們一直在努力學習你教我們的東西
we've been working really hard on what you taught us.
那好吧 來吧
Er... OK, go ahead.
歡迎來看我們的節目
Welcome to our assembly!
我們把自己粘在首相官邸前
We have glued ourselves to the Prime Minister's house
以示對氣候變化的抗議
to protest against climate change.
很好
Ha! Very good.
全球變暖是對地球最大的威脅
Global warming is the biggest threat to our planet, planet Earth.
我們能做些什么來阻止它呢
What can we do to stop it?
嘿 說你呢 你在干嘛
Hey, you! What are you doing?
我嗎 沒干嘛呀 不就是個塑料杯嗎
Me? Nothing. It's only plastic.
塑料快讓我窒息了
Plastic is slowly choking me...
它填滿了我的海洋 殺死了野生動物
..filling my oceans and killing wildlife.
那我該怎么辦
What can I do?
回收啊
Recycling!
接招
Take that.
我們回頭再回收他
We'll recycle him later.
哦 這么做可不行 九班的同學們
Oh, I don't think that's appropriate, Class 9.
你們在這把椅子上抹什么了
What have you done to this chair?
強力膠
Superglue.
你也是抗議的一部分 老師
You're part of the protest too, sir.
這一點也不好笑 凱莉 夠了 可以停了
That isn't funny, Ceri. All right, stop this now.
拯救地球的行動在上千年前就開始了
Saving the planet started thousands of years ago.
最初 地球女神
In the beginning, the Earth Goddess
是通過萬物表達自我的女神
was the one who expressed herself through the many.
她是廣闊的虛空 是萬物之始
She was the great void, the beginning of all things.
所有的靈魂都是 在她神圣的子宮里誕生的
All souls were born from her sacred womb,
在她的軀體所化的地球上 生活一段時間
lived for a span upon her body, the Earth,
死后再回到她的墳墓子宮里
then returned to her tomb-womb at death.
墳墓子宮
Tomb-womb?
抱歉 我想這不是第二階段教育的內容
I'm sorry, I don't think that's key stage 2.
可是金老師說
But Mr King said...
聽著 我不知道金老師是誰
Look, I don't know who this Mr King was
也不知道他教了你們什么 可這不正常 明白嗎
or what he was teaching you, but it's not normal, all right?
我會提交正式投訴
I'm going to make an official complaint.
現在麻煩你們把我從這椅子上放開
Now please get me out of this chair.
在15世紀
In the 15th century,
秘魯的兒童會被獻給神
Peru children were sacrificed to the gods
從而結束自然災害
to try and end natural disasters.
可是到了現代
But in modern times,
我們這些孩子要有自己的方式
we the children are demanding sacrifices of our own.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
等等 這就是你殺死蝌蚪的原因嗎
Wait, wait, is this why you killed the tadpoles?
-想阻止氣候變化嗎 -別說話了 金老師
-To try and end climate change? -No talking, Mr King.
我們是用耳朵聽 不是用嘴
We listen with these, not these.
我不是金老師
I'm not Mr King!
閉嘴 老師
Tight lips, sir.
不 不 不要
No, no, don't...
我們已經了解了可再生能源
We have learned about reusable energy.
我們了解了回收和再生
We have learned about recycling and rebirth.
約翰·巴雷康是第一個回收自我
John Barleycorn was the first man to recycle himself,
來回報地球恩賜的人 請聽他的故事
to replenish the Earth's bounty. This is his story.
三個人從西方走來
# There were three men come out of the west
用他們的財富做一件事
# Their fortunes for to try
他們鄭重起誓
# And these three men made a solemn vow
約翰·巴雷康該死
# John Barleycorn should die... #
這是怎么回事
What on earth is going on here?!
你們想干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我們在做演出表演 校長
We're doing our assembly, sir.
演出 那是下周的事
Assembly? That's not till next week.
你還好吧 柯蒂斯老師
Are you all right, Mr Curtis?
他們對你做了什么 你的嘴怎么了
What have they done to your mouth?
我們正要講約翰·巴雷康的故事
We were about to tell the story of John Barleycorn.
啊 我最喜歡的故事 接著講
Ah, my favourite part. Carry on.
約翰·巴雷康代表了自然界的生命循環
John Barleycorn represents the life cycle of the field.
他每年都會在豐收節開始時加冕
He is crowned once a year at the start of the harvest festival
被尊奉為玉米之王
and revered as the Corn King.
如你所發現的那樣
Last year, as you discovered,
去年獲得這個榮譽的是哈迪老師
Mr Hardy was given the honour.
今年該輪到你了
This year, the crown is yours.
我們發現你是大自然想要的
We discovered you are as nature intended.
沒有隔開 還裹著的那種
Uncut and still sheathed.
是新的玉米之王的理想候選人
A perfect candidate for our new corn king.
謝謝你 凱莉 你做得很好
Thank you, Ceri, you did it beautifully.
在退位之后 玉米之王會回歸大地
When his reign is ended, the King is returned to the land
以三種死亡為榮
and honoured with a triple death
淹死 勒死和肢解
drowned, strangled and dismembered,
他那筒體斷節被埋在田地里
his broken body buried in the field
以確保豐收
to ensure a fertile harvest.
就像是人豆
Like human beans!
沒錯 格溫 就像是人豆
Exactly, Gwen, like human beans.
你和那些倫敦人或許會拍拍肩膀
You and your fancy friends in London may pat yourselves on the back
說你們終于意識到了環境問題
that you've finally woken up to environmental issues, but...
可我們已經為地球犧牲幾百年了
..we've been doing our bit for the planet for centuries now.
來吧 孩子們
Come, children.
國王死了 國王萬歲
The King is dead. Long live the King.
國王萬歲
Long live the King!
溫妮 就等你了
Winnie, we're ready for you now.
我的韭菜會感激你的
You're going to do my leeks the world of good.
有三個人從西方走出來
# There were three men come out of the west
他們要財富做一件事
# Their fortunes for to try
他們鄭重起誓
# And these three men made a solemn vow
約翰·巴雷康該死
# John Barleycorn should die
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la la
他們推著他繞田地游行
# They wheeled him all around the field
他是受難的囚徒
# A prisoner to endure
可憐的巴雷康
# And in the barn poor Barleycorn
被放在谷倉的地上
# They laid him upon the floor
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
# Fa la la la la la la
他們雇了一個人 用酸蘋果樹的樹杈
# They hired men with the crab tree sticks
剝下他的皮
# To cut him skin from bone
磨坊主對他更糟糕
# And the miller, he served him worse than that
他把他放在兩塊大石頭中間研磨
# For he ground him between two stones
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la, fa la la la la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
# Fa la la la la la la... #